<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/blog</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/blog"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/blog/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2014-02-25T16:00:00-08:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Legal Malpractice Part 1: What is Legal Malpractice?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/blog/2014/02/26/Legal-Malpractice-Part-1-What-is-Legal-Malpractice/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/blog/2014/02/26/Legal-Malpractice-Part-1-What-is-Legal-Malpractice/</id>
    <published>2014-02-25T16:00:00-08:00</published>
    <updated>2014-04-13T15:49:00-07:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Over the next few articles, we'll be exploring the subject of legal malpractice. We'll look at some examples of legal malpractice cases, discuss what is needed to prove a legal malpractice case, and examine some issues particular to legal malpractice cases. But first, what is legal malpractice?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Legal malpractice occurs when a lawyer harms their client, either deliberately or by making errors that no reasonable attorney would make.  In legal-speak, malpractice is a deviation from standards of practice of the legal profession, when an attorney fails to demonstrate the level of care and skill of an ordinary practitioner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Legal malpractice doesn't just mean that your lawyer lost your case or didn't get you as much money as you think you deserved. Even if your lawyer made a mistake in handling your case, they may not have committed malpractice if they were acting in good faith. You must prove that your attorney made a serious error in judgment, was negligent, or intended to harm you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, you must prove that your lawyer's actions directly caused you to suffer damages. If your lawyer's mistake did not change the outcome of your case, then they cannot be held responsible for legal malpractice. In other words, &lt;em&gt;"No harm, no foul"&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, imagine that you've broken your arm in a car accident and you've hired an attorney to sue the other driver. Your lawyer forgets about your case and fails to file suit before the statue of limitations elapses. Under the law, you've missed your chance to sue the other driver.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your lawyer has certainly failed to demonstrate the level of care and skill of an ordinary attorney, so you should be able to win a malpractice suit against them, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe not. Suppose that you chose the &lt;a href="http://njinjuryattorneyblog.com/the-verbal-threshold-what-is-it-why-do-i-have-it-how-do-i-change-it/" title="The Verbal Threshold: What Is It? Why Do I Have It? How Do I Change It?" target="_blank"&gt;verbal threshold option on your car insurance policy&lt;/a&gt;. Roughly, the verbal threshold requires your injuries to be permanent in order for you to receive payment for them, and your broken arm fully healed long ago. Even if your lawyer hadn't missed the statute of limitations, you wouldn't have been able to win your case, so you won't be able to win a legal malpractice case against your lawyer, either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In future articles in this series, we'll discuss several examples in which legal malpractice has or has not occurred. We'll also take a more detailed look at the elements of malpractice, as well as what a plaintiff must prove to win a malpractice case. Finally, we'll explore some issues and recent developments specific to legal malpractice cases. Stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>When A Loved One Is Killed In An Accident</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/blog/2014/01/20/When-A-Loved-One-Is-Killed-In-An-Accident/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/blog/2014/01/20/When-A-Loved-One-Is-Killed-In-An-Accident/</id>
    <published>2014-01-19T16:00:00-08:00</published>
    <updated>2014-04-15T14:46:59-07:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The unexpected death of a family member as a result of an accident can present one with most difficult times. A family is left not only to mourn the loss of a spouse, parent, or child, but to bear the financial burden of the funeral costs and burial. If a loved one was killed in an automobile accident, a fall accident, or while on the job, you and your family may be eligible for compensation. Here is what you need to know:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Auto Accident&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When death occurs as a result of an auto accident, there are two sources of benefits. The automobile insurance policy of the deceased or a resident family member provides a death and funeral benefit as well as payment for all accident related medical bills. In addition, the party at fault for the accident may be sued for all damages flowing from the accident including pain and suffering, unpaid medical bills, and past and future wage loss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Fall Accident&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When death occurs due to fall down or complications due to the fall down, the insurance policy of the premises or property where the fall occurred may provide medical and funeral benefits. In addition, the owner of the property or premises can be sued for damages flowing from the fall if the fall occurred due to a defect or dangerous condition of the premises.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Work Accident&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When death occurs due to a work related accident, numerous benefits are available to the survivors of the deceased. These include a death benefit and a funeral allowance as well as dependency benefits to the worker’s spouse and children.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;How KDJ Can Help&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the Westfield, New Jersey, law offices of &lt;a href="http://kdjlawoffice.com"&gt;Kessler, DiGiovanni &amp;amp; Jesuele, LLP&lt;/a&gt;, we represent individuals and families involved in personal injury and wrongful death cases caused by the negligence or recklessness of others. Rather than attempt to be "all things to all people," we've dedicated our resources and time to personal injury law.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since our firm's establishment in 1966, we have worked to assist clients who find themselves facing an uncertain future due to a serious accident. In building our clients' cases, we work with investigators and a host of medical and scientific experts. Our efforts have resulted in significant financial recoveries for hundreds of clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you've lost a loved one in an accident, make sure that you and your family get all the help that you're entitled to. Give us a call at (908) 232-2040 or &lt;a href="mailto:kessler54@comcast.net"&gt;send us an email&lt;/a&gt; today.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Hurt On The Job? These Are Your Rights.</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/blog/2013/11/26/Hurt-On-The-Job-These-Are-Your-Rights/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/blog/2013/11/26/Hurt-On-The-Job-These-Are-Your-Rights/</id>
    <published>2013-11-25T16:00:00-08:00</published>
    <updated>2014-04-15T14:47:00-07:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Workers’ compensation is a “no fault” insurance program that provides, medical treatment, wage replacement, and permanent disability compensation to employees who suffer job-related injuries or illnesses. In New Jersey, virtually every employer is required to carry workers’ compensation insurance. Your boss should have supplied you with an information pamphlet on workers’ compensation when you began work.  Also, the law requires that information on workers’ compensation must be posted in a place visible to all employees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are hurt while at work, it is your responsibility to inform your boss or manager as soon as possible. Once your boss is notified of your injury, the law requires them to fill out an injury report to be submitted to their workers’ compensation insurance carrier. An injury report should include as many details as possible about the injury and what caused it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you require immediate medical treatment for your injuries, your employer (or their workers’ compensation insurance carrier) &lt;strong&gt;must&lt;/strong&gt; provide you with such treatment. &lt;strong&gt;Your employer and/or the insurance carrier have the right to choose the medical provider for your treatment&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, you should contact an experienced workers’ compensation attorney as soon as possible. Your attorney will file a claim petition, which begins the formal workers’ compensation process. Your case will then proceed under the direction of your attorney.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It is against the law for your boss to discourage you from reporting an injury, seeking medical treatment, or filing a claim petition.  It is also against the law for your boss to fire you, punish you, or otherwise retaliate against you for reporting an injury, seeking treatment, or filing a claim petition. If your employer does any of these things, they can be punished severely by the court.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have been hurt on the job, it is important for you to obtain an experienced workers’ compensation lawyer. Your lawyer will handle your claim as it moves through the system, and will help you get the compensation you deserve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been handling workers’ compensation cases for almost 30 years. If you have been injured at work, give me a call at (908) 232-2040 or email me at kessler54@comcast.net for a free consultation.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The Verbal Threshold: What Is It? Why Do I Have It? How Do I Change It?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/blog/2013/11/25/The-Verbal-Threshold-What-Is-It-Why-Do-I-Have-It-How-Do-I-Change-It/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/blog/2013/11/25/The-Verbal-Threshold-What-Is-It-Why-Do-I-Have-It-How-Do-I-Change-It/</id>
    <published>2013-11-24T16:00:00-08:00</published>
    <updated>2014-04-15T14:47:05-07:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The verbal threshold, also known as the limited tort, the lawsuit threshold or the tort limitation, is a product of one of the biggest hoodwinking scams in New Jersey history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A brief history is necessary. About two decades ago, automobile insurers were threatening to leave the State of New Jersey claiming that it was too costly to do business here. In response, they lobbied our Legislators in New Jersey to make it more difficult for those injured in automobile accidents to obtain fair compensation for their injuries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Former law had incorporated a monetary threshold. Under that system, if you were hurt in a car accident, you could only recover for your injuries if your medical treatment expenses exceeded either $200 or $1700, depending upon which option you chose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under pressure from the insurance industry, the Legislature imposed an entirely new threshold scheme. The public now had the option of selecting the "no threshold" or the "verbal threshold". Under the no threshold, any injury suffered in an auto accident entitled you to make a claim and recover fair value for your injuries. The verbal threshold, however, requires you to prove that in the accident you suffered death, dismemberment, significant disfigurement, fracture, loss of a fetus or any other injury, permanent in nature, which has not healed to function normally and will not heal to function normally with further treatment. (See &lt;a href="http://njlaw.rutgers.edu/collections/njstats/showsect.php?section=39%3A6a-8&amp;amp;actn=getsect" title="NJSA 39:6a-8" target="_blank"&gt;NJSA 39:6a-8&lt;/a&gt; for more details.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you made no active choice, as most policy holders did and still do, then the law provided you with a no threshold policy. If you actively chose the verbal threshold, you received a slightly lower premium but gave up important rights to sue for your injuries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, more knowledgable members of the public could make a choice to get better or worse coverage. Those less knowledgeable members of the public, who made no choice, were given the better "no threshold" by law.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several years later,  the insurance industry again lobbied the Legislature to change the law so that those members of the public who made no active choice on the threshold were given the poorer coverage; the coverage which restricts your right to seek fair compensation for your injuries - the verbal threshold. In return, the insurance lobbyists assured the Legislature that premiums for auto coverage would be significantly reduced. With that promise in mind, the Legislature changed the law so that those not making an active choice received the verbal threshold.  The result was that insurers paid out on less claims since nearly 85 percent of the public ended up with the verbal threshold. In addition, despite their assurances, auto insurance premiums continued to rise!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those of you reading this article are probably thinking to yourselves that you have never heard of the threshold scheme and don't know which threshold you have. In fact nearly 9 out of 10 of those reading this article are covered by the verbal threshold. Your rights have been restricted without your knowledge or consent courtesy of the Legislature, the very people elected by you to safeguard your rights. To be sure, our legislature should be embarrassed at being hoodwinked by the insurance lobbyists. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The verbal threshold can easily be manipulated by unscrupulous physicians hired by the insurance companies to defend auto injury lawsuits–so called “hired guns”. Since the question of whether an injury is permanent or not is based upon the opinions of doctors, the hired guns routinely write reports arguing that the injuries suffered by a litigant are not permanent. Quite frequently, these experts convince jurors that a personal injury claimant has not suffered permanent injuries and thus is not entitled to fair damages for their injuries. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can easily change the threshold by calling your agent or insurer directly and demanding an immediate change from the verbal threshold to the no threshold. While there is additional cost associated with the no threshold, it is well worth the additional premium. This change can be made at any time in your policy period, not only on renewal. You owe it to yourself and your family to be protected to the greatest extent provided by the law.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>What Is My Workers' Compensation Case Worth?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/blog/2013/03/07/What-Is-My-Workers-Compensation-Case-Worth/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/blog/2013/03/07/What-Is-My-Workers-Compensation-Case-Worth/</id>
    <published>2013-03-06T16:00:00-08:00</published>
    <updated>2014-04-13T15:49:00-07:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's the question that every injured worker wants answered: "What is my workers' compensation case worth?"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In New Jersey, there are two kinds of payments in a workers' compensation case:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Temporary disability&lt;/strong&gt;, paid while you cannot work because of your injury. It is paid at 70% of your weekly wage before taxes, and tops out at bit more than $810 a week.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Permanency awards&lt;/strong&gt; are paid for lasting disability due to work injury. They depend on the part of the body that is disabled, the level of disability, the medical treatment required, and other factors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are lots of factors which can affect the amount of a permanency award, but here is a &lt;strong&gt;rough&lt;/strong&gt; guide with some ranges of values for 2012:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Sprain of upper or lower back with conservative treatment (physical therapy): $9,720 - $16,200&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Herniated disc, neck or upper back with conservative treatment (physical therapy): $12,960 - $27,882&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Herniated disc, neck or upper back with epidurals: $19,440 - $32,226&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Herniated disc, neck or upper back with discectomy surgery: $19,440 - $42,106&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Herniated disc, neck or upper back with fusion: $47,646 - $79,380&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Sprain of shoulder with conservative treatment (physical therapy): $9,720 - $16,200&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Tear of internal structures (rotator cuff, labrum etc) with surgery: $23,964 - $42,106&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Sprain of knee with conservative treatment (physical therapy): $5,103 - $8,505&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Tear of meniscus, ACL of knee without surgery: $8,505 - $13,608&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Tear of meniscus, ACL of knee with arthroscopic surgery: $11,907 - $21,451&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Tear of meniscus, ACL of knee with open surgery: $13,608 - $23,964&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Carpal tunnel injury to one hand without surgery: $2,646 - $5,292&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Carpal tunnel injury to one hand with surgery for release: $3,969 - $7,938&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Carpal tunnel injury to both hands without surgery: $9,720 - $16,200&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Carpal tunnel injury to both hands with surgery on both hands: $19,440 - $27,882&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you've been injured on the job and you want to know what your workers' compensation case is worth, contact me. I've been handling these kinds of cases for almost 30 years and I can give you a good idea of how much you can expect to get paid. Visit &lt;a title="Kessler, DiGiovanni &amp;amp; Jesuele, LLP" href="http://kdjlawoffice.com"&gt;my firm's webpage&lt;/a&gt;, email me at &lt;a href="mailto:kessler54@comcast.net"&gt;kessler54@comcast.net&lt;/a&gt;, or call me at (908) 232-2040.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Is It Workers' Compensation or Workers Compensation?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/blog/2013/02/25/Is-It-Workers-Compensation-or-Workers-Compensation/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/blog/2013/02/25/Is-It-Workers-Compensation-or-Workers-Compensation/</id>
    <published>2013-02-24T16:00:00-08:00</published>
    <updated>2014-04-15T14:47:06-07:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've noticed that there seems to be a lot of confusion about the apostrophe in the phrase "workers compensation".  I've seen "workers compensation", "workers' compensation", and even "worker's compensation".  So which is correct?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, it depends on who you ask.  In both &lt;a href="http://lwd.dol.state.nj.us/labor/wc/wc_index.html" title="New Jersey Department of Labor, Division of Workers' Compensation"&gt;New Jersey&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.wcb.ny.gov/" title="New York Workers' Compensation Board"&gt;New York&lt;/a&gt;, the state uses the plural possessive: workers'. The website &lt;a href="http://grammar.ccc.commnet.edu/grammar/grammarlogs4/grammarlogs563.htm#10" title="The Grammar Logs"&gt;The Grammar Logs&lt;/a&gt; agrees that you should use workers'.  This is also the punctuation that &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Workers'_compensation"&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt; favors (though "workers compensation" is also used several times in the article, and there's a bit of a &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Talk%3AWorkers%27_compensation#The_Apostrophe" title="Wikipedia: Workers' Compensation Talk Page"&gt;debate&lt;/a&gt; on the Talk page).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, the &lt;a href="https://www.ncci.com/nccimain/pages/default.aspx" title="National Council on Compensation Insurance"&gt;National Council on Compensation insurance&lt;/a&gt;, which bills itself as "the largest provider of workers compensation and employee injury data and statistics in the nation," does not use the apostrophe.  Neither does &lt;a href="http://www.statefarm.com/insurance/business/workers-compensation-insurance.asp" title="State Farm Workers Compensation Insurance"&gt;State Farm&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="http://www.boltinsurance.com/business-insurance/solutions/workers-insurance-compensation/" title="Bolt Insurance Workers Compensation"&gt;Bolt Insurance&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The punctuation "worker's" is not very popular, but it still has its adherents, including the state governments of both &lt;a href="http://www.in.gov/wcb/index.htm" title="Indiana Worker's Compensation Board"&gt;Indiana&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://dwd.wisconsin.gov/wc/" title="Wisconsin Worker's Compensation Division"&gt;Wisconsin&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, the State of Colorado can't seem to make up its mind: &lt;a href="http://www.colorado.gov/cs/Satellite?c=Page&amp;amp;childpagename=DORA-DI%2FDORALayout&amp;amp;cid=1251623067619&amp;amp;pagename=CBONWrapper" title="State of Colorado DORA Division of Insurance"&gt;this page from their Division of Insurance&lt;/a&gt; uses all three punctuations! The federal government is also inconsistent; it &lt;a href="http://www.dol.gov/owcp/dfec/" title="Department of Labor Workers' Compensation"&gt;usually prefers "workers'"&lt;/a&gt; but &lt;a href="http://www.socialsecurity.gov/OP_Home/rulings/di/05/SSR-DI05toc.html" title="Social Security Rulings - Worker's Compensation"&gt;sometimes uses "worker's"&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then there's &lt;a href="http://www.riskinfo.com/warren/apostrophe.html" title="The Workers Comp Apostrophe"&gt;this guy&lt;/a&gt;, who says that all three are acceptable, and which one you choose depends upon your personality.  (Cute.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what's the verdict? There is support for all three punctuations, but "workers' compensation" seems to be the most popular by far, and it's the punctuation that I use as well.  Therefore, unless you have strong feelings on the matter, I'd advise you to write "workers' compensation".&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What punctuation do you prefer? Let us know in the comments!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
